<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Google | Andy Sinesio]]></title>
  <link href="http://asinesio.github.com/blog/categories/google/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://asinesio.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-17T00:43:43-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://asinesio.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Sinesio]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blink is not the coming of the apocalypse]]></title>
    <link href="http://asinesio.github.com/blog/2013/04/05/blink-is-not-the-coming-of-the-apocalypse/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-05T00:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://asinesio.github.com/blog/2013/04/05/blink-is-not-the-coming-of-the-apocalypse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since Google <a href="http://blog.chromium.org/2013/04/blink-rendering-engine-for-chromium.html">announced they were forking WebKit</a>, I've seen nothing but <a href="http://prng.net/blink-faq.html">universally negative reactions</a>.</p>

<p>The primary points seem to be that Blink is bad because:</p>

<h4>"Developers will now have another major browser rendering engine that they will need to test."</h4>

<p>This is just not true. If you're building quality web software, you are already testing your site on both Chrome and Safari (Mobile and desktop).</p>

<p>A <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Explorer_6">web monoculture</a> is bad for everyone.  A healthy web ecosystem consisting of equal parts Chrome, Safari, Firefox, Opera, and Internet Explorer means that the users will have a choice, because all web apps will generally need to work with all browsers.</p>

<h4>"WebKit and Blink will diverge and re-implement each other's features, thus slowing progress."</h4>

<p>Google already <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5490242">wasn't contributing</a> much of their code back to WebKit.  The announcement of Blink is truly just formalizing what was already happening.</p>

<h4>"Google is going to use this to invade my privacy and track me across the Web."</h4>

<p>Yes. They were doing that anyway, and they haven't exactly had a great <a href="http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2411916,00.asp">track record</a> of protecting your privacy. If you were concerned about this, you wouldn't be using Chrome anyway.</p>

<p>Think about it; Google forked WebKit for the same reason Apple replaced Google Maps - Google wants to control their own destiny.</p>

<p>Blink is not the coming of the web browser apocalypse (but it does have a terrible name).</p>

<p>The apocalypse happened when Internet Explorer crushed Netscape. We've recovered from that, and we're never going back.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
