<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: engineering | Andy Sinesio]]></title>
  <link href="http://asinesio.github.com/blog/categories/engineering/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://asinesio.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-17T00:43:43-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://asinesio.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Sinesio]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A software update is required.]]></title>
    <link href="http://asinesio.github.com/blog/2013/02/26/a-software-update-is-required/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T21:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://asinesio.github.com/blog/2013/02/26/a-software-update-is-required</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My brother gave me <a href="http://us.gran-turismo.com/us/">Gran Turismo 5</a> for Christmas.  I've played all of the other GT games and loved them. GT5 had been out for awhile, but I was still excited to give it a try.</p>

<p>I returned home from Christmas; after a few days, I finally had a free hour or two, so I booted up the PS3 and threw in the game.  And I was greeted by this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2013-02-26/ps3-update.jpg" alt="The latest update data was found." /></p>

<p><em>14 hours later</em>, the game finally finished updating and allowed me to play.  Too bad that I no longer had the free hour or two, so it took another week before I was able to actually play the game.</p>

<p>It reminded me of this nefarious monstrosity:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2013-02-26/windows-update.png" alt="Windows Update restart nag" /></p>

<p>"But, I don't want to update <em>at all</em>," I plead.</p>

<p>The system scoffs. "Tough shit, buddy.  You're going to have to deal with this now because I don't value your time."</p>

<!--more-->


<h4>This is the typical experience of today's console gamer.</h4>

<p>The advent of attached hard drives and broadband internet in consoles, without any software design, brought this ugliness from the PC to the living room.</p>

<p>It's so bad, in fact, that at Sony's ill-advised PlayStation 4 news conference, they made sure to announce that <a href="http://www.mcvuk.com/news/read/ps4-to-have-background-firmware-updates/0111249">background firmware updates would be part of the new system.</a>  This was astounding because they did not even <em>show any games or an actual PlayStation 4</em> -- but they mentioned background updates.</p>

<p>This isn't enough, though.  Updates also need to be <em>optional</em> and <em>taken at the user's convenience</em>.</p>

<h4>Will it matter?</h4>

<p>The sad thing is that this is just a microcosm of the usability issues with console systems.  Others:</p>

<ul>
<li>Insanely long load times.</li>
<li>A Herculean effort <em>just to type a password with a controller.</em></li>
<li>Exclusive use of a television set.</li>
<li>Expensive, silly, useless peripherals.</li>
<li>Lack of downloadable and affordable games.</li>
</ul>


<p>I don't see the next generation PlayStation addressing these issues.  Or the Xbox, for that matter.</p>

<p>That's why the iPad is the next generation console.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
